[Child] The handle remains...
(romantic Polish pop song)
(female vocals in Polish)
(low rumbling)
(door shop bell)
[in Polish]
(light organ music)
[Bethany in English] It's not
working.
[Rob] It's 1-3-Key-3-1-3-5.
[Bethany] Yeah, that's what I
did.
[Rob] You sure?
[Bethany] Rob...
[Rob] Right. Let me check the
email.
Okay. Right.
1-3-Key-3-1-5-5.
[Bethany] Okay.
Got it.
(light organ music)
It says there's a lock box on
the wall with the keys.
[Bethany] It's this, right?
[Rob] Yeah, I think that's it.
Yeah.
So, we're in apartment 13.
[Bethany] Does it say what floor
we're on?
[Rob] ...No.
[Bethany] Okay, because none
of these doors
have numbers on them.
[Rob] Is this it?
No.
Maybe it's this one?
[Rob] Yeah.
(keys jingling)
(low rumbling)
[Rob] Yep. Here we go.
Oh. Not bad.
Not bad.
This is great.
Yeah?
[Rob] Yeah.
(classical piano music)
Looks like the pictures, more or
less.
Yeah, this looks great.
I'm so happy to be here with
you.
Me too.
I love you, Bethany.
I love you, too.
You okay?
Yeah, no. I'm just, uh..
I hit a wall.
Just stress or I don't know,
packing late or something.
Yeah, it's okay, babe.
Yeah, I think I just need to lie
down, have a quick nap.
Yeah, that's fine.
Want to come with?
You know, I think I'm going to
go and explore actually.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm just, I'm not tired.
Okay.
You excited to be back?
Yeah, maybe that's it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Don't go too far.
And when I'm up, I'd love for
you to show me
all around Warsaw, Poland.
Alright?
Okay, babe.
Okay.
(light organ music)
[in Polish]
(approaching metro train)
(train announcement in Polish)
(screeching tram wheels)
(techno music beat)
(door shop bell)
(techno music from headphones)
(car horn)
(light organ music)
(dog barking)
(low rumbling)
(door knock)
(distant dog barking)
(light organ music)
(light organ music continues)
(birds chirping)
[Rob in English] It really is
beautiful.
I didn't expect Warsaw to be so
green.
[Bethany] "Dziekuje."
[Rob] "Dziekuje."
"Dziekuje."
[Bethany] "Dziekuje."
[Rob] "Dzie-KU-je."
"Dziekuje."
And how do you say "you're
welcome"?
"Nie ma za co."
And I love you?
"Kocham cie."
"Dziekuje."
"Nie ma za co."
-[Bethany] Hey, babe.
-Hey.
-Got you a coffee.
Cheers. Thanks.
Do you like it here or you
wanna find another spot?
Let's walk.
Yeah.
(light organ music)
[in Polish]
[Rob in English] Are you having
a good day?
[Bethany] Yeah.
In Warsaw, Poland.
Yes.
Is it as romantic as you
remembered?
Did I say that?
You said it was more romantic
than Paris... The city of love.
In Paris, there's just so much
expectation to be romantic
that it just isn't romantic
anymore.
[Bethany] Like, everyone's seen
the Eiffel Tower,
But...
Not everyone's sat on that
bench...
Or...
Looked at some random painting.
Beauty in a bench.
That's what I love about you.
(message notification sound)
We might have an issue.
Seems our flight's been
canceled.
Why has it been cancelled?
Volcanic ash.
Mount Etna erupted yesterday
in Italy.
Air travel has been suspended
over the next 72 hours.
I guess we'll have to
reschedule.
(ominous organ music)
(low rumbling and glass
rattling)
Here's to more time in Warsaw,
Poland.
Yeah.
[in Polish]
(light organ music)
(light organ music continues)
(people laughing)
(peeing in toilet)
[Rob in English] I need to drink
more water tomorrow.
(toilet flushing)
(classical piano music)
The flight's rescheduled.
The rental's extended.
Amazing.
Is anything on your mind?
No.
Did you enjoy today?
Mmhmm.
Just wait till you see what I've
got planned for us tomorrow.
I can't wait.
Good night.
(dishes rattling)
(low rumbling)
(rattling intensifies)
(distant police sirens)
[Bethany] Nel!
Can I come up?
[in Polish]
[Bethany in English] I don't
understand
a single thing you're saying.
[in Polish]
[in English] My boyfriend's
gonna propose.
Your boyfriend?
[Bethany] Tomorrow.
So why are you here?
Mount Etna erupted yesterday.
[Nel] And when exactly did you
arrive?
Yesterday.
Can I come up?
Okay, go to the gate
and type 4-Key-8-2-1-2.
(keypad beeps)
[Nel] Door on the right.
[Nel] The door's open.
So you are getting engaged...
I don't know.
That's why I came.
And, who is your boyfriend?
Rob.
Rob?
We live together in London.
I found the ring around a month
ago,
and
I knew he was going to ask me
soon because
he suggested we go to Paris
and I said, "what about Warsaw?"
The thing is that with him,
the earth doesn't shake
and
volcanoes don't erupt.
(playful electronic beat)
You look the same.
And you look different.
[in Polish]
(electronic beat intensifies)
(birds chirping)
(distant light traffic)
[in English] Bethany?
Bethany?
Morning.
How'd you sleep, love?
Good. Yeah. You?
Like a rock.
Good.
I have a big day planned for us.
But I know you don't like
surprises
and I don't want to
overwhelm you
so I am going to reveal them
to you
one at a time.
Okay?
Shall I tell you now?
Please?
First up,
professional massage.
Great.
(spa music)
[Masseuse]
I'll be back in five minutes.
Make yourself comfortable.
(door closing)
(phone ringing)
[Bethany] Hi.
[Bethany] Getting a massage.
[Bethany] Yes.
[Bethany] I did.
[Bethany] I don't know.
[Bethany] Will you?
[Bethany] I will.
[Bethany] Okay, bye.
[Rob] Who was that?
[Bethany] A friend in Warsaw.
[Rob] Nice.
After our massages we're going
to get some sushi, darling.
[Bethany] Mhmm.
(classical piano music)
You look nice.
Thank you.
[Rob] You visited L.J. before we
left. How's she holding up?
Kind of rough, actually.
The labor was really long and
intense.
Is the baby healthy?
What's her name again?
[Bethany] Her name's Greta.
And yeah, she's okay.
There are a few complications,
but nothing major.
Charles isn't handling it
well, though.
[Rob] Oh no...
[Claude] Excuse me.
You're British?
Yeah.
[Claude] Thought so.
I, um...
It's nice to hear English.
[Rob] It is, yeah.
You're American?
Mhmm.
What are you doing in Warsaw?
[Claude] I am...
painting.
I'm an artist.
[Bethany] Oh, cool.
We just went to the National
Museum yesterday.
Yeah. What did you think?
I loved it. I love 19th century
art.
Oh my, then you have to go by
the National Gallery.
It's amazing!
[Rob] Yes, Zacheta.
We're familiar.
[Claude in Polish] Zacheta.
[in English] What kind of
paintings do you make?
[Claude] All sorts.
Come by my studio today.
I'm throwing a party.
-Oh, cool.
-Yeah, it's just me and
some of my Polish friends.
That sounds fun.
That sounds fun, right?
[Rob] Yeah?
Yeah, sure.
If we could find the time.
[Bethany] Yeah, let's make the
time.
[Rob] Okay.
[Bethany] Great.
[Claude] Great.
(aggressive dance beat)
(car horn)
(dance beat continues)
[Rob] Would you like me
to reveal the next surprise?
[Bethany] Why not?
[Rob] I got us reservations
at Kieliszki na Próznej.
[Bethany] Oh. Cute.
[Rob] Do you know of it?
[Bethany] Never heard of it.
[Rob] Well, it's supposed to be
excellent.
It's from the Michelin Guide.
So we'll pop into the party,
say hello and be on our way?
[Bethany] Sounds like a plan!
[in Polish]
[in English] Hi.
Hi.
-[Nel] These are my friends.
-[Bethany] Hey.
-I'm Bethany. Hi.
-Nice to meet you.
-Bethany, hey.
-I'm Kuba. Nice to meet you.
Bethany is an old friend of
mine.
-[Friend] Oh really?
-[Nel] Mhmm.
What are you doing here?
[Nel] What are you doing here,
Bethany?
[Bethany] Uhh...
I met Claude at sushi earlier.
-Just like that?
-Yeah.
-Coincidence, I guess?
So, what are you doing tonight?
Are you partying?
(loud electronic music)
[in Polish]
(people laughing)
[Claude in English] I think that
a lot of the work that I do
comes from
come from this space,
this space of being,
immersed in a culture that's so
different from my own,
it helps me turn my brain off,
right?
And so when my brain is turned
off,
I can enter into a dream state
more, more naturally.
I'm trying to come up with the
title.
[in Polish]
[Claude in English] Hey, babe.
Hey! Love, uh...
How much longer do you want
to stay?
You know, I've got reservations
at 9:30.
Babe. Reservations? Let's just
have fun!
Hi, Rob.
(dance beat drops)
(light organ music)
[in Polish]
(ringback tone)
[Bethany in English] Hi, it's
Bethany. Leave a message.
[Rob] Hi love.
I stepped out for a moment.
I just needed to clear my head.
I'm back at the party now,
and I don't see you anywhere.
Let me know, okay? Bye.
(ringback tone)
[Bethany] Hi, it's Bethany.
Leave a message.
[Rob] Hi, love.
Again, I'm sorry I stepped
away.
I may have been a bit dramatic.
I'm wondering where you are...
Okay, bye.
(ringback tone)
[Bethany] Hi, it's Bethany.
Leave a message.
[Rob] Hi, love.
The party ended and I've left.
My plan is to head home and
hopefully I'll see you there.
I'm really struggling with this
right now.
Please call me.
And let me know you're okay.
(distant thunder)
(unlocking door)
Bethany?
(message notification sound)
[in Polish]
[Bethany in English] Morning.
Morning.
Are you okay?
[Bethany] I'm fine.
Do you want some coffee?
[Bethany] So who's the girl in
the pictures?
It's Ula.
Who's Ula?
A friend.
She still around?
Yes.
That a good thing?
I don't know.
Let's go somewhere.
[Nel] I can't.
I have to open the flower shop.
Do you really though?
(playful electronic beat)
[in Polish]
[in English] Wait, so, you knew
each other before my party?
That's crazy.
[Rob] That's crazy!
[Nel] You know what's crazy?
Every time we get together,
crazy coincidences happen.
Okay? Like what?
A volcano erupts.
[Claude] Excuse me,
I don't think I'm following.
[Bethany] So, the first time we
met,
that volcano in Iceland erupted.
(ominous organ music)
[Bethany] I was 16 and I was
here on a school trip,
and the volcano erupted so I
got stuck here for a month.
[Bethany] It was amazing.
[Nel] Yeah, and it was so dark
all the time
because of all the ash in the
sky.
[Claude] Damn. Okay.
Then we saw each
other again around a year later
And that volcano in Chile
erupted.
[Nel] Uhh, Cordón Caulle?
Cordón Caulle.
And then after that,
it was the Wolf in Ecuador
and Taal in the Philippines.
So, did something happen this
time or...
[Nel] Etna two days ago.
So... you're saying
you're like magic?
We like to joke that we're
making it happen.
[Claude] Mmm.
What's the joke?
Volcanoes kill people.
(ominous tone)
(phone ringing)
[Nel] Rob's calling.
Just let it go to voicemail.
[Nel] Okay, so, what is the
problem with Rob?
I told you.
No volcanos.
No magical coincidences.
But does he treat you nice?
Yeah. I mean,
he's really nice.
Sometimes nice is nice.
Yeah, but sometimes nice is
boring.
[Bethany] Do you ever think
about leaving Warsaw?
[Nel] I thought about it
but I love Poland
so I could leave but I would
come back.
You should think about leaving.
It can be a really positive
experience.
Yeah, I will think about it.
(ominous organ music)
(door shop bell)
[in Polish]
[in English] Hi.
[Bethany] Hi, Maja.
Good to see you again.
Yeah. You too.
[in Polish]
(ominous organ music)
(party music beat)
[Nel in English] Okay.
This is the last one.
[Bethany] Maybe it's the last
one.
[Nel] No, no, it's the last one.
[Bethany] Okay.
We'll see if it's the last one.
[Bethany] On three, we're
gonna drink.
Okay?
One, two, three, drink.
What's up with that guy?
It's this guy. His name is Jan.
[Bethany] Hey, Jan!
What's wrong?
[in Polish]
-[in English] What's he saying?
-Uh, he's saying his
girlfriend had dumped him,
His heart is broken
and it is the end.
[Bethany] Aw...
Tell him "It's okay
and there's going to be plenty
more coming his way."
[in Polish]
[in English] What's he say now?
[Nel] He says, "Thank you very
much."
[in Polish]
[in English] So
can I stay at yours again
tonight?
Of course you can.
[Bethany] One more?
[Nel] This is the last one!
[Bethany] Maybe it's the last
one!
(chillwave music)
(door unlocking)
[in Polish]
(phone ringing)
[Bethany in English] Hi, it's
Bethany. Leave a message.
[in Polish]
(low rumbling)
[Bethany in English] I had a
dream,
which was not all a dream.
The bright sun was extinguish'd,
and the stars
Did wander darkling
in the eternal space,
Rayless
and pathless,
and the icy earth
Swung blind and blackening
in the moonless air;
Morn came, and went-
and came,
and brought no day,
(ominous tones)
And men forgot their passions
in the dread
Of this their desolation;
and all hearts Were chill'd into
a selfish prayer
for light:
And they did live by watchfires-
and the thrones,
The palaces of crowned kings-
the huts,
the habitations of all things
which dwell,
Were burnt for beacons;
cities were consumed,
(ominous tone continues)
I'm gonna go to bed now.
(low rumbling)
(ringback tone)
[in Polish]
[Rob in English] Bethany?
(light organ music)
(car horn)
(low rumbling)
Hi, Claude. It's Rob.
We met at the sushi restaurant
a couple of days ago,
and I came to your party.
Yeah...
Yeah, it's nice to see you.
Uh, may I come in for a moment?
Sure.
-Yeah?
-Alright.
[Claude] What's up?
Do you remember my girlfriend
from the other night, Bethany?
Yeah.
Do you know where she is?
[Claude] Is something wrong?
[Rob] No. No, she's okay.
Um...
[Rob] It's just
well, we came to Warsaw to
well, for, um...
[Claude] Had you been here
before?
[Rob] She had.
But...
To be honest,
I was hoping this would be a
good place to propose.
[Claude] Warsaw.
Yes.
[Rob] She said it was romantic.
Not Krakow?
[Rob] No.
No.
Warsaw,
Poland.
[Rob] And...
everything was going well,
basically,
until we came to your party.
[Rob] But then she became
cold and distant and
I know that I stepped out for a
moment to collect myself,
but I just can't seem to find
the reason
why she would behave this way.
[Claude] Have you met Nel?
Is that the, um, blonde woman?
Yeah.
No, no, I didn't meet her.
Although I saw that they were
enjoying each other's company.
(phone ringing)
[Claude] Hey, we were just
talking about you.
[Nel] We?
I'm with Bethany's Rob.
He's looking for Bethany.
[Nel] You want to bring him
here?
[Claude] Where are you?
[Nel] The flower shop.
[Rob] Great.
See you soon.
[Nel] Bye.
[Claude] That's crazy.
[Claude] This kind of um,
synchronicity...
these coincidences...
I think that those are vestiges
of our youth.
Interesting.
[Claude] It's, um...
It's a way to make sense of the
world when you're a little kid
that they, for some reason, held
on to
maybe they need, like, therapy.
Maybe because they, um,
don't have religion. None of us
do.
You know, that's why all these
different cosmologies-
But she's never said anything
like this to me.
I mean,
listen.
I think there's a lot she hasn't
said to you.
(light organ music)
[Nel] When we were 16,
Bethany came to Warsaw for a
school trip.
And while she was here,
a volcano erupted.
We said we did it.
And it became this joke we had
together.
Because every time we got
together, a volcano erupted.
We thought it was so fun.
We would go out.
We would ditch work.
We would cheat on our partners.
And whoever we were dating
would find out.
Or we would get fired.
But we didn't care
because this volcano told us
that we are special.
But this isn't a joke.
Volcanoes do kill people.
[Nel] And they cause so much
destruction
and they leave perfectly nice
boyfriends in the dust.
Rob, Bethany found the ring.
So, why bring me all the way to
Warsaw, Poland?
[Nel] Because if she comes to
Warsaw, then a volcano erupts.
(light organ music)
[Rob] Okay, so a volcano
erupting
means you're not accountable
for your actions.
Great.
This is where I was going to
propose.
Seemed nice in the pictures.
Do you want to see the ring?
Yeah.
It's great.
[Nel] It's nice.
(classical piano music)
[in Polish]
[Rob in English] Just want you
to know I'm not the kind of
person who has big emotional
explosions or anything.
[Rob] But I keep wondering if it
was me
who did something wrong.
[Nel] No.
And basically, you just went
dancing?
Yes.
[Rob] And she's done this
before?
[Nel] Mhmm.
[Rob] Right.
This really isn't about me.
[Nel] So there is this girl.
Uh huh, what's her name?
Ula.
I like her.
She's very nice.
It's good.
Yeah, we've been off and on for
a while.
She just got back to Warsaw.
Yeah? When?
On Sunday.
[Rob] Sunday?
The day we arrived.
And the day Etna erupted.
Interesting.
Maybe Etna was Ula?
[Rob] You know, I actually
looked it up.
There are fifteen hundred active
volcanoes on earth
and fifty to seventy of them
erupt each year.
That's basically one eruption
per week.
Really?
[Rob] Yeah.
Okay.
When do you plan to see Ula
again?
I don't know. No plans at the
moment.
Oh, you've got to have a plan.
Why don't you take my
reservations
for lunch tomorrow?
I was supposed to surprise
Bethany.
[Nel] Where?
It's Opasly Tom?
[Nel in Polish] Opasly Tom?
[in English] Yeah.
What?
That's where my first date with
Ula was.
(light organ music)
[in Polish]
(ringback tone)
[Bethany in English] Hi, it's
Bethany. Leave a message.
[Rob] Morn came, and went-
and came, and brought no day,
And men forgot their passions
in the dread
Of this their desolation;
and all hearts
Were chill'd into
a selfish prayer for light:
And they did live by
watchfires-
and the thrones,
The palaces of crowned kings-
the huts, the habitations of
all things which dwell,
Were burnt for beacons;
cities were consumed,
And men were gather'd round
their blazing homes
To look once more
into each other's face;
Happy were those who dwelt
within the eye
Of the volcanos,
and their mountain-torch:
A fearful hope
was all the world contain'd;
Forests were set on fire-
but hour by hour
They fell and faded-
and the crackling trunks
Extinguish'd with a crash-
and all was black.
(approaching footsteps)
[in Polish]
(romantic Polish pop song)
(train announcement in Polish)
(female vocals in Polish)